<codelist name="CollaborationType" xml:lang="en" complete="1">
    <metadata>
        <name>
            <narrative>Collaboration Type</narrative>
        </name>
        <url>http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/dacandcrscodelists.htm</url>
    </metadata>
    <codelist-items>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>1</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Bilateral</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Bilatéral</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Bilateral transactions are those undertaken by a donor, excluding core contributions to other organisations (codes 2 and 3 below). It includes transactions channelled through other organisations.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>2</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Multilateral</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Multilatéral</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Multilateral contributions are those made to a recipient institution which: 
    i. conducts all or part of its activities in favour of development; 
    ii. is an international agency, institution or organisation whose members are governments, or a fund managed autonomously by such an agency; and 
    iii. pools contributions so that they lose their identity and become an integral part of its financial assets.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>3</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Bilateral, core contributions to NGOs and other private bodies / PPPs</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Contributions bilatérales au budget général d'organisations non gouvernementales, d'autres organisations de la société civile, de partenariats publics-privés et d'instituts de recherches</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Bilateral funds paid over to national and international non-governmental organisations (NGOs), Public Private Partnerships (PPPs), or other private bodies for use at their discretion.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>4</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Multilateral outflows</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">apports des agences multilatérales</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Aid activities financed from the multilateral institutions' regular budgets.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>6</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Private sector outflow</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">apports du secteur privé</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative/>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>7</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Bilateral, ex-post reporting on NGOs' activities funded through core contributions</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Contributions bilatérales, notification ex post des activités des ONG financées par des contributions des donneurs au budget général de l'ONG.</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative/>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
    </codelist-items>
</codelist>
